As routers are added to networks, configurations
are changed.
As routing tables are updated automatically
and manually, routers need to receive the
most recent updates to the overall network
topology.
A process called convergence does this.
In this process, a root bridge router learns
the topology of the entire network and then
distributes that topology to the remaining
routers on the network.
The process can take several seconds, so if
one notices a temporary slowdown in network
performance, specifically after either physical
or logical topology changes have taken place,
convergence is probably taking place at that
time within the network.
Normal traffic flow should resume once convergence
has been completed.